Arpita Gouswami

Loughborough | 07584512364 | arpitagouswami@gmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | GitHub

PERSONAL PROFILE

Self-Motivated, Enthusiastic and Result-orientated willing to discuss the position of Developer. The opportunity presented is very appealing as it allows me to broaden my career horizons and reveal my creative spirit. My uncanny interest and experience in web development, strong desire to connect my future profession with creative field and entire passion to brush up my knowledge motivate me to apply. I believe my ability to tackle hard tasks, flexibility and dedication to the work do make me a suitable candidate for this position.

EDUCATION

ULSTER UNIVERSITY, BIRMINGHAM

FEB 2020- SEPT 2021

INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MANAGEMENT WITH ADVANCE PRACTICE

Modules: International Finance, Global Business, Digital Landscape, International Marketing, Global Strategy, Applied Research Skills, International HRM, International Entrepreneurship.

DE MONTFORT UNIVERSITY, LEICESTER MASTER'S IN COMPUTING

OCT 2017- JUL 2019

Modules: Object Oriented Programming, Database System & Design, Computer System and Networking, Systems Analysis and Design, Human Factors in Systems Design, E-Commerce Software, E-Commerce Systems, Research, Ethics And Professionalism

INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT UNIVERSAL TECHNICAL CAMPUS, INDIA

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

SEP 2013- JUL 2015

SIGMA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY & ENGINEERING, INDIA DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

SEP 2009- JUL 2012

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DESIGN INTERNSHIP AT ATOZ VIRTUAL

JAN 2022- PRESENT

- Design Company Website with WIX Platform.
- Carried Out Design Concepts, Wireframes, Interaction Prototype, And Visual Design.
- Collaborated With Team and Implementing New Features and UX.
- Performs Other Related Duties as Assigned.

JUNIOUR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT GUJ INFOTECH, BORSAD, INDIA

DEC 2015 -AUG 2017

- Writing code to develop Desktop applications, using HTML5/CSS3 and Java Script.
- Gathering information from consumers about program functionality.
- Supported and maintained the software within an IT system once it was in full operation.
- Monitored the effects of any changed code to see if it has affected the performance of any related software or systems.
- Produced an estimate of the time it will take to develop and implement any software updates.

PROJECTS

> Personal Investment Manager

2015

Technologies used: Frontend- Asp.net 2010 with C#, Backend-Microsoft SQL server 2008

- Designed an interactive application using Asp.net with C#.
- With this App people can manage their finance or organize cash flow, expenses, and bank accounts in one place.
- This project Personal Investment Manager includes creating groups as you like. For e.g., your investment in IPO, Mutual Fund, Loan, LIC, share market, Credit Card. Money Tracking helps you to calculate your expanses, premiums, profit, loss using graphs & charts.
- Learned and implemented the fundamental concept of data visualization, data preparation, model implementation and model evaluation.

Weather App

- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and Weather API.
- People can check weather from anywhere or anytime with help of this app.
- Learned how to use API to access weather data to create a forecast, including temperature.

Password Generator

- Create password generator with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- With help of this we can establish a random or customized password for users.

Quote Generator

- Generate with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Fit Api quote.
- Users can get new quote and establish on twitter or share with friends.

SKILLS

- Relationship building
- Problem solving
- Time management

- Teamwork and collaboration
- Decision making
- Flexibility and adaptability

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Asp. Net (Basic), CSS, HTML5, Java Script, j-query, Bootstrap, UI/UX, WordPress
- Java, C, C++ (Basic), PHP, SQL, ORACLE

CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy Certification of the Complete Web & Mobile Designer in 2022:UI/UX, Figma, +more.	2022
Udemy Certification of the Complete Web Development Course 2.0	2021
Oracle Certification of Web Component Development with Servlets & Jsps Java EE 6	2013
CISCO Certification of CCNA Exploration: Network Fundamentals.	2014